Dr. Andy Galpin here and welcome back
to five
physiology a series right a complicated
physiological strength and conditioning
nutrition topics of breaking down for
you in less than five minutes are
roughly five minutes
day's topic physiology of found no
wonder how fat loss actually what I mean
by that is how was it actually possible
to lose weight or imagined in my belly
stuck out here and I want them some
training on jerking program now it's
where did that face the world go to the
loser now most people would say well
it's diet and exercise not but that's
actually what you do today want to talk
about on this nearly the methods inhabit
you pick but the physiology of the
adaptation I think we do that
understand better what to actually
happen what's occurring and fat wow it's
not coming from sweat we don't
chronically lose fat that way it's not
coming from your ppl who put up for that
matter but it's getting up off of your
body somehow figured out yet
do something on the count of three why
not take a big deep breath and hold it
let it go 92123 in or not
congratulations you are just got a
little tiny bit what's actually
happening there cuz that's right you
heard me correctly you lose fat my
breathing and stretching back to the
beginning here everything is made of
long carbon chains like the fat in your
body the carbohydrate your body you can
see from these pictures are representing
the bread is carbohydrate fat cheese and
the protein is the burner I know those
on exactly what's in those things but
you get the idea
well carbohydrates whether they're in
your body or 13 the food you're
consuming sustain our six carbon chain
the most part 6 carbon chain is also
used the big monkey a lot more crimes in
the point is so users though image over
here this by Arvind Jain represent no
matter what Mac Observer talking about
the let's talk about fast what happens
when you breathe in primarily o2 oxygen
and you bring up primarily co2 the
differences farm where is that Carmen
come from
will actually comes from your fat
storage so they were talking about the
again car when you're eating everything
out what what you're really trying to do
what you all you need to do is to
consume less carbon and you breathe out
of course this is why it's important to
have an excellent diet and exercise
program to effectively lose fat because
this is what actually happened so I
imagine this card machines were a big
piece of fat in your body like this this
picture here's five pounds five pounds
of muscle let's say you want to get rid
of that fat five-pound path and we know
it's a big long Gina carpenter presented
by this what I'm going to do is break
off one of those arms and your body is
animal let carmen float around their
free plane will have to deal with it but
because I broke that all on one level we
break the chemical bond here we have the
net release of entered case we use that
energy to then make eight of the
molecule called atp use up to power
exercised body wants or needs and is not
an extra got a reaction we get a net
result of what we're left with is
free-floating carbon I mentioned so you
breathe in that go to because you know
co2 plays very commonplace very very
oxygen to form co2 and o2
out co2 and that carbon literally was
your fat now that process of breaking up
a carbon energy folks that's exactly
what metabolism oK so that's something
like this again he got their
free-floating carbon it binds to some
oxygen you exhale and now because my fat
pad used to be this big which was safe I
pardons long even know the answers like
five million little by little as we
continue to choke off those carbons
what's happenin to the science of our
fat is literally getting smaller and
smaller and smaller so will simply
continue this for as long as possible so
either again consuming less carbon or
increase in the rate at which so if you
to finish on this idea of ok so we'll
talk to check in a separate talk but I
need less carbon that's great not CaRMS
more carbon and carbohydrate and protein
food period but the exiled portion of
the thing about this way what's the best
type of exercise for fat loss is it
something like over in the corner that's
a long duration of cardio is there
something maybe more like this little
something maybe like circuit training or
intervals about something over here
maybe something more like true strength
rating or answer isn't this exactly the
same question is the most important
factor is adherence in other words what
are you with a client working with most
likely to actually do that's the program
you want to put them now of course
reality of it is a good program an ideal
program probably has a combination of
all three of these at least some of the
combination based on personal preference
what are you more likely to do all
simply about burning car
talk that he not all three of these
modes are exactly equal but at a basic
level were talking about working with
the masses because as long as everything
they're losing fat that exciting news
the more information about it definitely
check out the 25 minute physiology and
the 55 minutes and geology of fat loss
those are available as well
questions online on social if not enjoy
share with your friends
passing information that's keeping
inspiring people to reach their health
and fitness goals on education and other
things like this so we'll see you next
time thanks for the support